<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="kurmannu@ethz.ch">Ueli Kurmann</author>
		<title>User Guide: iGesture Workbench</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<a name="cp:userguide"></a>
		<h1>User Guide: iGesture Workbench</h1>
		<h2>Workbench</h2>
		This chapter gives an overview of the graphical iGesture tool
		shown in Figure
		<a href="#fig%3Aitoolshot">1</a>
		. The workbench is started with the shell script located in the bin folder of the binary distribution available at <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/igesture">Sourceforge</a>.
		<p>
			<a name="fig:itoolshot"></a>
			<div>
				<div align="center">
					<img src="images/userguide/screenshotTool.png" />
					<center>
						<br />
						Figure 1: Screenshot iGesture tool
						<br />
					</center>
				</div>
			</div>
		</p>
		<h2>Capturing Gestures</h2>
		Most tabs contain a capture area as shown in Figure
		<a href="#fig%3Acapture_area">2</a>
		. It displays the gesture that has been been captured most
		recently by a specific input device. The input device can be selected
		from the list on the left-hand side. The gesture input can be
		used for various tasks as described in the following sections.
		<p>
			<a name="fig:capture_area"></a>
			<div>
				<div align="center">
					<img src="images/userguide/capture_area.png" />
					<center>
						<br />
						Figure 2: Capturing a gesture
						<br />
					</center>
				</div>
			</div>
		</p>
		<h2>Tabs</h2>
			<subsection name="Gesture Set Tab">
				<p>
					The
					<i>Gesture Set Tab</i>
					enables us to administrate gesture sets, classes and
					descriptors. This view as shown in Figure
					<a href="#fig%3AscreenShotAdmin">3</a>
					has two main components which are always visible.
					These are an area to define the gesture and a tree structure to manage
					the gesture sets and classes.
					<p>
						<div>
							<div align="center">
								<img
									src="images/userguide/screenshotAdminTab.png" />
								<center>
									<br />
									Figure 3: Screenshot Gesture Set tab
									<br />
								</center>
							</div>
						</div>
					</p>
					<p>
						Gesture classes can be created and
						deleted in the list. These operations are
						accessible over a context menu. For editing a
						gesture class, select the descriptor of the gesture 
						class and a new view opens visualising the descriptor.
						The descriptors can be edited and deleted as well.
					</p>
					<p>
						The tree representing the gesture sets and the
						containing classes has several context menus for
						the operations create, delete, export and import
						a gesture set and to add gesture classes.
					</p>
					<p>
						The export and import functionality of set level
						allows creating and reading XML files containing
						the set and the corresponding classes with their
						descriptors. These files can be used for
						initialising the recogniser and makes it
						therefore independent of the storage manager.
					</p>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Test Bench Tab">
				<p>
					The
					<i>Test Bench Tab</i>
					shown in Figure
					<a href="#fig%3AscreenShotRecogniser">4</a>
					provides functionality to acquire a gesture from the
					input device and recognise it with the gesture set
					and algorithm of the user&apos;s choice. This
					enables a simple and quick test of specific
					gestures. All gesture sets of the currently opened
					database are available and the algorithms can be
					selected.
				</p>
					<p>
						<div>
							<div align="center">
								<img
									src="images/userguide/screenshotRecogniser.png" />
								<center>
									<br />
									Figure 4: Test Bench tab screenshot
									<br />
								</center>
							</div>
						</div>
					</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Batch Processing Tab">
				<p>
					A batch process can be used to determine the most suitable values for the 
					algorithm parameters. To run a batch process, a batch configuration must be 
					provided, a gesture and test set has to be selected and an output directory 
					for the batch process report can be specified. The report itself is also 
					displayed at the bottom after the batch process has finished.
				</p>	
				<p>
					<div>
						<div align="center">
							<img
								src="images/userguide/screenshotBatch.png" />
							<center>
								<br />
								Figure 5: Screenshot Batch Processing tab
								<br />
							</center>
						</div>
					</div>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Test Set Tab">
				<p>
					The
					<i>Test Set Tab</i>
					shown in Figure
					<a href="#fig%3AscreenShotTest">6</a>
					can be used to create test sets for testing
					algorithms and their configuration (e.g. in a batch process). It also has a
					capture component and a list of available test sets and classes.
					<p>
						<div>
							<div align="center">
								<img
									src="images/userguide/screenshotTestTab.png" />
								<center>
									<br />
									Figure 6: Screenshot Test Set tab
									<br />
								</center>
							</div>
						</div>
					</p>
					<p>
						Test sets can be created, edited and deleted.
						Furthermore, we provide functionality to export
						and import test sets from the corresponding XML
						representation.
					</p>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Composite Test Bench Tab">
				<p>
					The <i>Composite Test Bench Tab</i> is used to test the recognition of composite gestures. One or more
					<i>Recognisers</i> can be created by selecting one or more algorithms, gesture sets and devices that send 
					their captured input to the <i>Recogniser</i>. Then the <i>Multi-modal Recogniser</i> can be configured with
					a gesture set with composite gestures and the recognition process can be started. The recognition results are
					displayed on the bottom.
				</p>
				<p>
					<div>
						<div align="center">
							<img
								src="images/userguide/screenshotComposite.png" />
							<center>
								<br />
								Figure 7: Screenshot Composite Test Bench tab
								<br />
							</center>
						</div>
					</div>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Device Manager">
				<p>
					The <i>Device Manager</i> shown in Figure <a href="#fig%3Adevman">8</a> provides functionality
					to add and remove users and devices. Devices can also be disconnected and reconnected manually. It 
					is possible to associate a user with a device. If you have a fixed setup, it is possible to save this
					setup to and load it from file. A wizard is used to add a device manually.
				</p>
				<p>
					<div>
						<div align="center">
							<img
								src="images/userguide/screenshotDeviceManager.png" />
							<center>
								<br />
								Figure 8: Screenshot Device Manager
								<br />
							</center>
						</div>
					</div>
				</p>
			</subsection>


	</body>
</document>
