<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="igesture@uelikurmann.ch">Ueli Kurmann</author>
		<title>Download</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
		We provide different builds of iGesture hosted on SourceForge.
		<a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/igesture/">
			<img
				src="http://sflogo.sourceforge.net/sflogo.php?group_id=188690&amp;type=2"
				width="125" height="37" border="0" alt="SourceForge.net Logo" />
		</a>
		<section name="Stable Version">
			<p>
				If you are an iGesture newcomer we recommend to download the most recent stable version. 
				It is a preconfigured eclipse project and contains all necessary third-party libraries as well as the sources of the framework, 
				the tool, gesture sets and some demo applications. All demo applications should be runnable out of the box. 
				The stable version can be downloaded <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/igesture/files/">here</a>. 
				The source code, the tool and the libraries can be downloaded separately as well.
			</p>
			<p>
				Demo gesture sets are also available at SourceForge in the iGesture 1.0 release 
				(<a href="http://downloads.sourceforge.net/igesture/igesture-1.0-sample-data.zip">igesture-1.0-sample-data.zip</a>). 
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Development Version">
			<p>
				For advanced users we recommend to use the sources available in the SVN repository hosted at Sourceforge. 
				The sources and libraries are organised in a Maven project. Information about the SVN repository is 
				available <a href="http://igesture.org/source-repository.html">here</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Maven is a dependency management tool and can be used from the command line. The following table contains 
				some of the most frequently used commands. More information about Maven can be found <a href="http://maven.apache.org/index.html">here</a>. 
				An Eclipse plug-in for Maven can be found <a href="http://m2eclipse.sonatype.org/">here</a>
			</p>
			<p>
				<div>
					<table>
						<tr>
							<td>
								Compile Maven project
							</td>
							<td>
								mvn compile [-U]
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>
								Clean Maven project
							</td>
							<td>
								mvn clean
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>
								Package Maven project to a jar
							</td>
							<td>
								mvn package
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>
								Install Maven project into local Maven repository
							</td>
							<td>
								mvn install
							</td>
						</tr>

						<tr>
							<td>
								Generate a project web site
							</td>
							<td>
								mvn site
							</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					<center>
						<br/>
						Table 1: Frequently used Maven commands
						<br/>
					</center>
					
				</div>	
			</p>
			<p>
				
			</p>		
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
