<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="kurmannu@ethz.ch">Ueli Kurmann</author>
		<title>Composite Gestures</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Composite Gestures">
			<p>
				For each gesture that forms part of a composite, it is possible to 
				define by which user it should be performed, by what kind of device 
				and even by what specific devices. Note that at the moment we only 
				support composite gestures of one level deep.
			</p>
			<subsection name="Specified Composite Patterns">
				<table>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Concurrency</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Two or more gestures are performed concurrently.
							All gestures that are part of the composite must 
							be performed with an overlap in time.
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Sequence</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Two or more gestures are performed in sequence.
							The minimum and maximum gap time between two 
							consecutive gestures must be specified.
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Interval</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Two or more gestures are performed within a 
							certain time interval. As a parameter the time 
							interval must be defined.
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Cardinality</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Within a certain time interval, a particular 
							gesture must be performed between a minimum 
							and maximum number of times. This pattern can
							be used to define a threshold or a majority. 
							Two versions are 
							available, either each device has only one vote or
							either each user has only one vote (a single user 
							can use multiple devices). The device manager
							is used to associate users with devices.
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Proximity Concurrency</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Two or more gestures are performed concurrently 
							and close to each other. The minimum and maximum 
							length of the diagonal of the (largest face of the) 
							bounding box of the
							different gestures has to be specified.
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>
							<b>Proximity Sequence</b>
						</td>
						<td>
							Two or more gestures are performed in sequence 
							and close to each other.The minimum and maximum 
							length of the diagonal of the (largest face of the) 
							bounding box of the
							different gestures has to be specified.
						</td>
					</tr>

				</table>

			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Design Guidelines">
				<p>
					When designing composite gestures, make sure that one composite 
					cannot form part of another composite, e.g. a sequence can form 
					part of an interval composite.
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>


</document>
