<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="kurmannu@ethz.ch">Ueli Kurmann</author>
		<title>Device Manager</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Device Manager">
			<p>
				The <i>Device Manager</i> provides support for managing users and 
				devices. A device can be manually added through a wizard. The first 
				step is to select a connection type. The devices are detected by 
				the corresponding discovery services. The following sections explain 
				the different configuration files.
			</p>
			<subsection name="Connection Types Configuration">
				<p>
					Each connection has a name which is displayed in the wizard and 
					a discovery service represented by the name of the class that 
					implements the discovery service.
				</p>
				<source>
&lt;connections&gt;
	&lt;connection&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;discoveryService&gt;
			org.ximtec.igesture.tool.view.devicemanager.discoveryservice.BluetoothDeviceDiscoveryService
		&lt;/discoveryService&gt;
	&lt;/connection&gt;
	&lt;connection&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;Tuio 2D&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;discoveryService&gt;
			org.ximtec.igesture.tool.view.devicemanager.discoveryservice.Tuio2DDeviceDiscoveryService
		&lt;/discoveryService&gt;
	&lt;/connection&gt;
	&lt;connection&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;Tuio 3D&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;discoveryService&gt;
			org.ximtec.igesture.tool.view.devicemanager.discoveryservice.Tuio3DDeviceDiscoveryService
		&lt;/discoveryService&gt;
	&lt;/connection&gt;
&lt;/connections&gt;
				</source>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Example Device Configuration">
				<p>
					Each connection type can support multiple devices. For example, different kinds of devices can be connected 
					through a Bluetooth connection such as the Wii Remote, digital pens and mobile phones. Each kind of device 
					can be implemented by a different class. In order to instantiate the right class if a device was detected by 
					the discovery service a mapping must be defined.
				</p>
				<p>
					The configuration below is used for Bluetooth devices. Most Bluetooth devices have a minor and major device class
					to identify the type of device. An example major device class is a computer, while the minor device class corresponding 
					to that major class can be desktop or laptop. However not all devices have been identified with a major and minor device 
					class, therefore the name of the device is used instead. This does mean that all devices of that type should have the
					same name or each device has to be added separately to that list. The class to instantiate is also mentionned.
				</p>
				<source>
&lt;devices&gt;
	&lt;device&gt;
		&lt;minor&gt;4&lt;/minor&gt;
		&lt;major&gt;1280&lt;/major&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;Nintendo RVL-CNT-01&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;class&gt;org.ximtec.igesture.io.wiimote.WiiReader&lt;/class&gt;
	&lt;/device&gt;
	&lt;device&gt;
		&lt;minor&gt;0&lt;/minor&gt;
		&lt;major&gt;1536&lt;/major&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;Pen LZ7064501GN&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;class&gt;org.ximtec.igesture.tool.view.devicemanager.BlueToothReader&lt;/class&gt;
	&lt;/device&gt;
	&lt;device&gt;
		&lt;minor&gt;0&lt;/minor&gt;
		&lt;major&gt;0&lt;/major&gt;
		&lt;name&gt;DP-201&lt;/name&gt;
		&lt;class&gt;org.ximtec.igesture.tool.view.devicemanager.BlueToothReader&lt;/class&gt;
	&lt;/device&gt;
&lt;/devices&gt;
				</source>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>


</document>
