<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- 
	index.xml - Welcome to iGesture
	
	Copyright 2005-2007 ETH Zurich. All rights reserved.
	
	This software is the proprietary information of ETH Zurich.
	Use is subject to license terms.
	
	@(#) $Id$
-->

<document>

	<properties>
		<author email="kurmannu@ethz.ch">Ueli Kurmann</author>
		<title>iGesture: A General Gesture Recognition Framework</title>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section
			name="iGesture: A General Gesture Recognition Framework">

			<p>
				While there exists a variety of gesture recognition frameworks,
				none of them addresses the issues of supporting both application
				developers as well as the designers of new recognition algorithms.
				iGesture supports the application developer who would like to add
				new gesture recognition functionality to their application as well
				as the designer of new gesture recognition algorithms. The iGesture
				framework can easily be configured to use any of the existing
				recognition algorithms (e.g. Rubine, SiGeR) or customised gesture
				sets can be defined. Furthermore, our test bench provides tools
				to verify new gesture recognition algorithms and to evaluate their
				performance.
			</p>
			<p>
				iGesture is a Java-based gesture recognition framework focusing on
				extensibility and cross-application reusability by providing an integrated
				solution that includes the iGesture recognition framework as well as the
				iGesture tool component for the creation of specific gesture sets. The iGesture
				tool further enables the evaluation and optimisation of new or existing gesture
				recognition algorithms.
			</p>
			<p>	
				The iGesture framework is not limited to a specific input device. In addition
				to traditional screen and mouse-based interaction, iGesture provides functionality
				for handling digital pen and paper input. iGesture also provides support for the 
				Wii Remote and for <a href="http://www.tuio.org">TUIO</a> devices.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section
			name="We would like to hear from you">

			<p>
				Are you using iGesture as part of your project? Then tell us about your project and how you are using iGesture. 
				Feedback or suggestions are also welcome. Or are you interested in becoming an iGesture developer, then don't hesitate 
				to contact us!
			</p>
		</section>


	</body>

</document>
